Get ready please standby, master course first episode Dr. Kang Chung Gyu stand by in three, two, one.
I run K Dental clinic, I am doctor Kang Chung Gyu.
I have graduated in 1987, so I've been a dentist for approximately 30 years
Because I was given this first lecture, I feel a lot of stress but I feel honored at the same time.
Master course is the same as navigation in terms of implant world even if you have never done implant surgery
You'd be able to place the implant in the correct position and do appropriate prosthesis.
You'd be able to maintain it correctly and prevent any complications even after a long period
I'll try my best to provide the guidelines in an organized way
The contents, Why do you need implants?
Dental implant advantages and disadvantages, what is a dental implant? Indication and Contradiction,
History of Dental Implants will be looked at and then I'm going to address what is Osseointegration.
I'm sure some of you know it, it's very basic but at the same time it's very important so we're going to gloss through it.
Let's think, Why do you need implant?
Before implant became more available we provided bridges and dentures.
However, as implant became more commercialized the implant can cover a lot of disadvantages of bridges and dentures
and it has its own advantages , in the missing area implant can provide optimum function that is why implant is necessary
First, let's look at a couple of clinical cases and think of why we need implants
This is the first case, this patient has been using denture for a long time. The patient came in so this was the state.
On the right, surveyed bridge was separated and the crown post fell out. For a long period in the missing area concentrated force was applied,
and as a result the survey the bridge was dislocated and it fell out.
If the patient received implanted treatment from the start in the top left, the surveyed crown would have remained as a natural tooth,
and the bridge tooth the patient would have been able to use it for a long time.
Let's look at a second case, In the lower left quadrant the two molars were missing and the two teeth on the front that surveyed the crown was used and a partial denture was used
as the patient used this for a long period a problem erupted in 2009, the patient used it like this and after seven years when the patient came in within the surveyed bridge there was the cementation and caries occurred and re-treatment was required
The root itself was sound re-endo treatment was done and implant was done in the missing area
If the patient had received implant treatment from the start of the two surveyed crown patient would have maintained natural teeth for a long time.
Let's look at the third case, in the three missing areas seven unit bridge was done as you can see this was long and in number 24 and 25 the surveyed crown tooth it was the clinical crown was very short
and decementation occurred and there was mobility
I removed the bridge and when I did re-treatment I could not do bridge, so in the front and the back the survey crown was changed with crowns and in the center the missing area two implants were placed
and two months later prosthesis was delivered, this is before treatment and the implant was used for re-treatment and prosthesis was delivered
If the patient had received implant from the beginning, the surveyed crown area on right and left, they would have remained as natural teeth for a long period.
Let's look at a fourth case, the two teeth in the middle were missing and six unit bridge was done and after a long time period
and after a long period fracture occurred in the center and re-treatment was required in the missing area two implants were placed and prosthesis was delivered
In this patient if the missing was restored with the implants from the beginning the adjacent teeth would have remained as healthy natural teeth.
Fifth case, the most distal molar was missing. The two teeth in the front cantilever bridge treatment was done and the past implant treatment was not done frequently and this was done instead.
However, in the most distal area when there's occlusing force, the tooth in the front the leverage force is applied there and the cementation occurred and carius was observed
re-treatment was required the tooth in the front I did endo treatment crowns were placed in the two teeth and in the missing area implant was placed.
This is the same for the patient if implant treatment was done ahead in the front would have been maintained as natural teeth.
Six case, this patient has using a partial denture in the upper and lower for a long time and the patient chief complaint was that the patient experienced too much pain to chew anything.
Telescope crown was done and the patient was wearing denture in upper and lower.
If you look at the patient when the denture was removed on the pot there is a very severe sore spot and whenever there was food in it would be stimulated and the patient was not able to have a meal because of pain.
Implant was placed and immediate loading was done and final prosthesis was delivered
If you look at the completed image the palette has been restored to a normal state and when the patient chooses the patient does not fell any pain and can eat with ease.
In the lower was removed and in the missing area implant was placed, immediate loadin was done and prosthesis was completed.
If implant treatment had been provided from the start for this patient would not have experienced such difficulty or pain and would have been able to eat as if he or she was using their natural teeth.
There's a final as you can see on the left the teeth are missing and on the right implants were placed and unilateral mastication was done.
Due to overload on the implant as you can see in red.
Radial lucid line was observed
On the left implant treatment was done two years later as you can see. As shown in red, radial loosened area has disappeared and the normal bone has been formed.
Most dental disease is caused by overloading and it's obvious to experienced clinicians it's especially so for periodontal diseases.
If you do implant treatment overload is not applied and force is disperesed. So the remaining teeth can be used in a sound manner for a long time.
In missing area implanted treatment is the optimum option.
Let's look at pros and cons in detail of implant treatment.
First, compared with denture, what advantages do implants have.
As you know, there's irritation, discomfort is very significant and it stimulates the softer tissue and people have resistance towards denture.
Another problem is that the most distal abutment receives most of the load from the missing area and it can lead to problems.
On the other hand, regarding implant it's very similar to natural teeth and it has stronger masticating force compared denture.
Five to seven times stronger, denture compared with natural teeth it's approximately 20 percent and as for implants it's 80 percent and it can restore masticating force in that way.
Implant forces dispersed and the lifespan of remaining teeth can be improved. If you looked at the multiple literature.
rpd 's average lifespan is approximately five to ten years and for abutment it's approximately five years so it's shorter
Let's look at another Korean literature according to the conclusion rpd if it  is meticulously, you can use it for seven to nine years.
However, if it is not maintained properly it is not as long and as for abutment it becomes shorter. The lifespan is approximately three to five years.
This needs to be discussed with the patient in advance.
The bridge and implant let's compare the two.
The bridge you need to prep the abutment and the occlusing force goes to abutment.
If you use it for a long time the cementation of abutment can occur as well as periodontitis.
According to literature, 20-years survival rate of three unit bridge is 73 percent and the main reason of failure is curious.
And this is due to decementation caused by long-term overload on abutment, such situation can occur more frequently if the path is bad among abutment and if clinical crown is short.
As shown, in three unit bridge on the abutment caries can occur as well as periodontal disease.
or abutment fracture. Such situations can occur frequently.
On the other hand, natural teeth can be maintained if you use implant and overload is not applied to abutment so adjacent teeth can be in a healthy way.
Let's compare bridge and implant, bridge in missing area the abutment on both sides overload is applied there however if you use implant treatment force is dispersed.
Let's look at the first case, In this patient number 16 was missing and three unit bridge was done.
One day the chief complaint that the upper right side of the patient experience discomfort and pain due to decementation and abutment caries occurred.
And as you can see caries occurred with time and endo treatment was required and retreatment was required.
as we did re-treatment the tooth was slightly mesially tilted, orthodontic treatment was done and number 17 endodontic treatment was done.
An implant was placed prosthesis was delivered two years and six months later and results are still stable.
The same patient in the upper left quadrant in number 27 the crown there was perforation and re-treatment was required.
In this case, bridge treatment should not be done. So crown treatment was done in missing area implant removal was done.
If you look at the second case, this is one of the biggest side effects of bridges.
So, in the upper right there's an order and the patient also complained of pain when the patient was chewing.
And there was periodontal disease in the abutment area.
Mobility was very severe due to periodontal disease and tooth was extracted and in that area, in order to place the implant immediately effort was made.
However, the bridge was very narrow so socket preservation and gbr was done.
Five months later when we revisited the site, primary closure occurred nicely and now we can place the implant.
Implant was placed prosthesis was delivered.
If you look at before and after appropriate gbr and socket preservation was done.
Originally it was a difficult implant case but the situation has turned favorably.
Ways to achieve such a favorable change, will be addressed in a gbr sample and advanced course.
Implant is not without shortfalls. Let’s look at disadvantages of implant depending on patient and dentist perspectives.
From the patient perspective, the treatments cost is quite expensive. However, these days implant treatment can be ensured.
And the treatment cost has reduced. So this is not a huge factor.
Second, the treatment period, compared with other prosthodontic treatment implant treatment can take slightly longer.
At minimum two months to three months. So it's slightly longer than prosthodontic treatment.
Additionaly, there's a fear of surgery. From a dentist perspective compared with other treatment it requires a lot of clinical knowledge and experiences.
Second, if it fails it is difficult to achieve full recovery or period of treatment can become elongated.
Thorough oral hygiene and regular check up is also essential.
However, implants has many advantages and it can overcome such disadvantages.
Now, let's talk about what is dental implant.
Implant is what you put in, if you look at the word let's look at the etymology.
im - inside and plant which is planting.
It's a mixture of these two words so implant stands for what you put inside human body.
It can be dental implants, intraocular lens or aritificial joint.
They can all be considered as implants. Let's compare graft and implant.
Graft stands for vital material inserted into the body to replace organ, kidney transplant, or liver transplant you can think of graft in line with these.
As for implant, it's non-vital material inserted into a body to replace a certain organ.
It includes metal, silicone, and plastic.
regarding metal, for dental titanium is used frequently.
Let's look at dental implant, it replaces the root of missing and our body does not resist this artificial tooth.
If a healthy tooth you to caries needs to be extracted in order to restore it we can use dental implants.
Let's look at indication and contraindication.
Implant indication includes complete edentulous rich, partial edentolous rich, and missing single tooth.
All cases where teeth are missing implant can be applied.
Contraindication, it's the same with other dental surgery. If there's a systemic disease that cannot be controlled or if there psychological issues.
Implant treatment cannot be provided unlike general surgery. Implant is directly related with bone.
So implant treatment cannot be provided to growing patients, also special care needs to be paid for osteoporosis patients.
Implant treatment can be provided in cases where teeth are missing and if the patient wants it and if systemic health is favorable.
Such treatment can be provided.
History of dental implants
let's look at them briefly.
In the ancient days, rock and ivory was used the dead or as a temporary measure.
In the medieval days, it's kind of funny but tooth from another person. In other words, tooth of a poor would be taken out and would be transplanted on the rich.
In my opinion, It had very low success rate.
Modern day implant, let’s look at history.
It started from 1930s, multiple materials and shapes of implants were used and developed.
The most important modern day implant concept was first established by Brony Mark in 1965.
On the left is the patient who received surgery for the first time and on the right is professor Browny Mark.
Osteo-integrated implant was first started by professor Brony Mark.
In 1952, in a room to university sweden a orthopedic professor Browny Mark as an effor t to understand bone healing process.
He put titanium optic chamber in rabbit's leg. When the research was over several months later, he tried to remove the chamber.
However, he couldn't because he was stucked in the bone.
And he named this phenomena Osseo-integration.
Osseointegration
It is direct structural and functional connection between living bone and implant.
As you can see, there's nothing in between bone and implant.
This is Osseointegration.
On the right, in the middle there's soft tissue in other words fibrous encapsulation has occurred and this leads to failure in Osseointegration.
Osseointegration, on the surface of the implant of the soft tissue is not attached and is firmly fixated that's called osseointegration.
As shown on the surface of the implant directly new bone is formed.
This is a sem image and you can see new bone is formed directly on the implanted surface.
There's a very important terminology BIC which is Bone to implant contact area.
Total length of implant surface by new bone to implant contact length is BIC.
it shows how well osseointegration has occurred, it's shown in percentage.
The higher the BIC, the better the osseointegration.
So when you develop new surface with animal study, you check whether the BIC has increased and whether the osseointegration has improved.
As you study implant, this is something that is going to come up repeatedly, so you should remember this point.
Additionally in 1981, on osseointegration and the importance of it. Six criteria have been released.
First, biocompatibility of implant materials, implant design, and implant surface. These three are realted with material.
Fourth, the stated of the bone is related to the patient.
Fifth, surgical procedure. Sixth, load condition.
The last two are related to the surgeon.
The details will be addressed in basic course and offline course.
Let's look at the summary of what was discussed.
This has been the first lecture of implant basic course.
At first, it may seem difficult and foreign but if you have accurate to aim and purpose and continue to advance forward
You'd be able to get good results.
Master course will help you find your way.
I hope you continue to show interest, Thank you fo watching.